<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hackintosh on Igor Kulman</title>
    <link>/tags/hackintosh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hackintosh on Igor Kulman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>igor@kulman.sk (davidmacias)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>igor@kulman.sk (davidmacias)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 09:29:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/hackintosh/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My experience running a hackintosh</title>
      <link>/my-experience-running-a-hackintosh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 09:29:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>igor@kulman.sk (davidmacias)</author>
      <guid>/my-experience-running-a-hackintosh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I decided to take part in an iOS project. The first problem I needed to solve was to be able to run macOS Sierra and XCode. I did not really want to buy an overpriced MacBook without function keys or and underpowered Mac Mini. Especially when I own a more than 3 years old desktop computer that is still usable for all my needs. A few iOS developers I know recommended I go the Hackintosh way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hackintosh&#34;&gt;Hackintosh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackintosh is PC that runs macOS. This configuration is not supported by Apple but it is possible if you have the right hardware since Apple has been using a fairly standard PC hardware for the last couple of years. &lt;s&gt;For example you cannot us any new GeForce 10X0 (Pascal) because there are no Apple computers with those new graphic cards so there are no drivers yet&lt;/s&gt; (NVIDIA has released &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tonymacx86.com/threads/nvidia-pascal-graphics-drivers-released-buyers-guide-updated.219153/&#34;&gt;new drivers supporting all the Pascal graphic cards&lt;/a&gt;). But if you have an older GeForce like me or an integrated one, you will be fine. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tonymacx86.com/&#34;&gt;tonymacx86.com&lt;/a&gt; website, basically the central hub of all the Hackintosh information, regularly publishes a buying guide that can be useful if you want to buy a new computer and install macOS on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not wish to install macOS directly on your hardware you can run it in a virtual machine, but the performance will never be very good. Some people do it for Xamarin development when they just need to compile their project and run the simulator, so there are a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://aurir.wordpress.com/2016/11/20/how-to-setting-up-macos-x-sierra-on-virtualbox-for-xamarin-development-with-visual-studio/&#34;&gt;tutorial on how to do it&lt;/a&gt;. There is also an interesting blog post series about a &lt;a href=&#34;https://arktronic.com/weblog/2016-12-10/virtual-hackintosh-part-1-the-concepts/&#34;&gt;virtual hackintosh&lt;/a&gt;. I tried running macOS in WMWare on my Thinkpad T440s but the performance was not good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-macos-sierra&#34;&gt;Installing macOS Sierra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed a bigger SSD anyway so I bought a new 500 GB SSD and cloned my Windows installation to it using CloneZilla. That way I got a spare old 128 GB SSD that I decided to use to install macOS Sierra on my desktop computer with this quite old configuration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gigabyte Z77 DS3H&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i5 3570K (4 core)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 GB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ASUS GTX 660&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;128 GB SSD (macOS), 500 GB SSD (Windows), 1TB HDD (data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tonymacx86.com/threads/unibeast-install-macos-sierra-on-any-supported-intel-based-pc.200564/&#34;&gt;created a installation disk&lt;/a&gt; on a friend&amp;rsquo;s iMac and I was surprised the installation only took about 20 minutes. I then injected the correct drivers for GPU (Nvidia), sound card and Ethernet and everything worked. You just need to know your hardware to be able to choose the correct drivers and you will be fine with the setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed macOS on a separate SSD, so I had no problem with the UEFI loader conflicting with Windows. The only problem is that my Windows 10 install is MBR not UEFI so Clover (the Hackintosh UEFI loader) cannot run it. I solved it by having the SSD with Windows as primary boot device so Windows boots automatically when I turn on the computer. When I want to boot macOS I just press F12 to get to the BIOS boot menu and choose the macOS drive to boot from manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance&#34;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I performed some tests with the few benchmarks that have both a Windows and a macOS version and the results were quite similar. There was basically no performance degradation on the macOS. I compared my Geekbench 4 results to the Apple hardware and I was quite surprised. My more than 3 years old desktop computer had basically the same single core performance score as a i5 MacBook Pro (13-inch Late 2016) and about 20% better multicore performance as this MacBook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it is not fair to compare desktop computers to laptops (desktop i5 has 4 cores, laptop i5 only 2) but I am still amazed that the current generation overpriced i5 MacBook Pro does not have a better performance that my more than 3 years old desktop. And I still have some room for overclocking. I think &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13797042&#34;&gt;Apple has really given up on machines for developers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-macos-and-software&#34;&gt;Using macOS and software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was surprised that basically everything worked out of the box. I had some problems getting my microphone to work but I finally solved it basically by accident when reading a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/hackintosh/comments/4gp7mj/need_help_getting_alc887_microphone_working_el/&#34;&gt;reddit thread&lt;/a&gt;. I even got iMessage working &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tonymacx86.com/threads/an-idiots-guide-to-imessage.196827/&#34;&gt;following this quite long tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Windows keyboard &lt;a href=&#34;using-macos-with-a-windows-keyboard&#34;&gt;needed some setup&lt;/a&gt;. The back and forward buttons on my gaming mouse do not work, but I got around it using &lt;a href=&#34;http://sunpech.com/2015/04/map-your-mouses-back-and-forward&#34;&gt;BetterTouchTool&lt;/a&gt;. If you have a WiFi card (I do not) it will probably not work. There are some alternatives you can use, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.de/Bluetooth-PCI-Express-BCM94360CD-Hackintosh-Flughafen/dp/B00MBP25UK/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1487424169&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=Hackintosh&#34;&gt;this WiFi card with Bluetooth that even support hand-off&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software like XCode also runs fine, including iOS simulators. Overall macOS behaves just like it was installed on an Apple machine. The macOS updates also work without a problem, just check &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tonymacx86.com/&#34;&gt;tonymacx86.com&lt;/a&gt; before applying them to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using macOS with a Windows keyboard</title>
      <link>/using-macos-with-a-windows-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 09:29:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>igor@kulman.sk (davidmacias)</author>
      <guid>/using-macos-with-a-windows-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you start using macOS after years of using Windows there are some things you expect to work in certain ways. One of those things is the ways the OS handles keyboard input and keyboard shortcuts. This is especially important if you still also use Windows and use a Windows keyboard with macOS. Here are a few things regarding the keyboard that help me when using macOS working on a side project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;control-option-and-command-keys&#34;&gt;Control, Option and Command keys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fist thing you may notice when using macOS with a Windows keyboard is that the modifier keys are not in the right order. The order of the modifier keys on an Apple keyboard is Control, Option, Command but the Ctrl, Windows, Alt keys on a Windows keyboard map to Control, Command, Option by default. You can fix the order of the modifier keys in System Preferences | Keyboard | Modifier keys&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/macoskeymapping.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;correctly-working-home-and-end-keys&#34;&gt;Correctly working Home and End keys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a programmer you probably use Home and End keys to navigate to the beginning and end of the current line a lot. Those keys work differently on macOS, pressing them will make your cursor jump to the beginning or the end of a file and drive you nuts. Luckily, there is quite an easy way to fix it. Create a &lt;code&gt;DefaultKeyBinding.dict&lt;/code&gt; file in &lt;code&gt;~/Library/KeyBindings&lt;/code&gt; to remap them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div data-gist=&#34;8b7ccbb32a639b7fdb2efaa5f4b02d6d&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is best to logout and log back in for the apps to notice this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use the Terminal app (you should really try &lt;a href=&#34;https://hyper.is/&#34;&gt;Hyper&lt;/a&gt; instead) this change will not work. You have to go to Preferences | Settings | Keyboard for the Terminal app and add &lt;code&gt;\033[H&lt;/code&gt; to move to the beginning of the line and &lt;code&gt;\033[F&lt;/code&gt; to move to the end of the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;volume-controls&#34;&gt;Volume controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows keyboard do not usually have Volume up and Volume down keys but you can quite simply create custom keyboard shortcuts for this functionality using Automator. Open Automator and create two Services executing Apple script. One for Volume up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div data-gist=&#34;871c92d9fdadf8dea25d4bbbae28ce66&#34; data-file=&#34;volumeup.applescript&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and another one for volume down&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div data-gist=&#34;871c92d9fdadf8dea25d4bbbae28ce66&#34; data-file=&#34;volumedown.applescript&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can then open System preferences | Keyboard | Keyboard shortcuts | Services and assign those two services any keyboard shortcut you want. I use Control + Command + Up for Volume up and Control + Command + Down for Volume down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/volumeshortcuts.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>